<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xavier Valcarce</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Xavier Valcarce</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quantum bound on the CHSH inequality: NPA in Julia with NCTSSOS</title>
      <link>/posts/npa_julia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/npa_julia/</guid>
      <description>The CHSH inequality is used to grasp the non-local nature of bipartite games in which each party perform one out of two dichotomic measurements on a shared state. The Tsilerson bound of the CHSH inequality is the maximum violation of this inequality under the best quantum strategy [1]. I.e. the highest CHSH score that can be obtained over all quantum states and measurements.
Finding the best CHSH score can be seen as an optimization of a polynomial of non-commutative variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python - LP/SDP for Quantum Information with PICOS</title>
      <link>/posts/picos_quantuminfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/picos_quantuminfo/</guid>
      <description>SDP interface and Solver PICOS is the Python interface I recommend to write/solve LP/SDP problem. It is under the GPLv3 free-license, probably supports your favorite solver, has crucial features for quantum information and, most importantly, has an attentive and friendly developer community.
Regarding SDP solvers, I had best performance with MOSEK. Sadly, this solver is proprietary (if price is of your concern, MOSEK offers a free one-year license for students). CVXOPT is a relatively good free-licensed alternative to MOSEK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup DNSCrypt with NetworkManager</title>
      <link>/posts/dnscrypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/dnscrypt/</guid>
      <description>To avoid your ISP eavesdropping on website you visit and other url you try to resolv, using privacy friendly DNS server is a necessity.
dnscrypt-proxy supports the encryption of your DNS request over HTTPS, and makes use of the DNSCrypt protocol. Here is a small guide to set this up alongside NetworkManager.
Installation Install the dnscrypt package provided by your distribution:
+ dnscrypt-proxy for ArchLinux
+ dnscrypt-proxy for Debian-based distribution</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Xavier Valcarce 🌐 valcarce.fr gitlab.com/plut0n xavier.valcarce _at_ unibas.ch
 Interests Quantum Information Theory, Quantum Computing and Communication, Machine Learning, Numerical Analysis
 Experiences  Aug. 2020 to present PhD student at Institut de Physique Théorique, CEA, CNRS, Université Paris Saclay under the supervision of Nicolas Sangouard
Publications:
- Self-testing two-qubit maximally entangled states from generalized CHSH test arXiv:2011.xxxx Sept. 2018 to Aug. 2020 Research Assistant (w/ a Master Degree) at Quantum Optics Theory Group (Nicolas Sangouard), University of Basel (Basel, Switzerland)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xavier Valcarce</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>Interests Quantum Information Theory, Quantum Computing and Communication, (Quantum) Machine Learning
 Experiences  Aug. 2020 to present PhD student at Institut de Physique Théorique, CEA, CNRS, Université Paris Saclay under the supervision of Nicolas Sangouard
Publications:
- Self-testing two-qubit maximally entangled states from generalized CHSH test arXiv:2011.03047
Talks &amp;amp; Conferences:
- Qhack 2021 - Participation to the Qhack challenges (qualified) - GDR IQFA&#39;11 - Poster on Robust self-testing of the singlet Sept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julia - One-Time Pad (XOR)</title>
      <link>/posts/onetimepadjl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/onetimepadjl/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer This is a pet project to help me understand the relatively new programming language Julia. I don’t guarantee that the code in this blog post is optimal, nor respect all Julia conventions.
Algorithm objective An implementation of the one-time pad encryption algorithm, based on the XOR gate. The code should be able to encrypt any given file by generating a key of this file’s size and XORing the file with the key, bit-by-bit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
