<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xavier Valcarce</title>
    <link>localhost/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Xavier Valcarce</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="localhost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>localhost/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>localhost/about/</guid>
      <description>Xavier Valcarce 🌐 valcarce.fr gitlab.com/plut0n xavier.valcarce _at_ unibas.ch
 Interests Quantum Information Theory, Quantum Computing and Communication, Machine Learning, Numerical Analysis
 Experiences  Aug. 2020 to present PhD student at Institut de Physique Théorique, CEA, CNRS, Université Paris Saclay under the supervision of Nicolas Sangouard
Publications:
- Self-testing two-qubit maximally entangled states from generalized CHSH test arXiv:2011.xxxx Sept. 2018 to Aug. 2020 Research Assistant (w/ a Master Degree) at Quantum Optics Theory Group (Nicolas Sangouard), University of Basel (Basel, Switzerland)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xavier Valcarce</title>
      <link>localhost/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>localhost/resume/</guid>
      <description>Interests Quantum Information Theory, Quantum Computing and Communication, (Quantum) Machine Learning
 Experiences  Aug. 2020 to present PhD student at Institut de Physique Théorique, CEA, CNRS, Université Paris Saclay under the supervision of Nicolas Sangouard
Publications:
- Self-testing two-qubit maximally entangled states from generalized CHSH test arXiv:2011.03047
Talks &amp;amp; Conferences:
- Qhack 2021 - Participation to the Qhack challenges (qualified) - GDR IQFA&#39;11 - Poster on Robust self-testing of the singlet Sept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julia - One-Time Pad (XOR)</title>
      <link>localhost/posts/onetimepadjl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>localhost/posts/onetimepadjl/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer This is a pet project to help me understand the relatively new programming language Julia. I don’t guarantee that the code in this blog post is optimal, nor respect all Julia conventions.
Algorithm objective An implementation of the one-time pad encryption algorithm, based on the XOR gate. The code should be able to encrypt any given file by generating a key of this file’s size and XORing the file with the key, bit-by-bit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
